A Guide to the Guy Davenport Papers 1956-1983
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Guy Davenport Papers 1956-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10539-m,n
170 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Glen Horowitz, Bookseller, on 1988 March 8.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of manuscripts, letters, drawings, and miscellaneous papers, 1956-1983, of American writer Guy Davenport. Letters to Laurence Scott, 1956-1983, discuss Davenport's life and literary endeavors. Topics include teaching at Haverford College and the University of Kentucky; his interest in Ezra Pound, T.S. Eliot and Louis Agassiz; his reading; his translations from the Greek; his friends, students and family; and his sexual encounters. Stan Brakhage, Hugh Kenner, Marianne Moore, Eudora Welty, Jonathan Williams, and Louis Zukofsky are mentioned frequently. Several letters are illustrated.
The collection also contains six haiku, 1960-1961, by Davenport, and nine drawings.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series. Series I and II, Manuscripts and letters are arranged chronologically; Series III, drawings are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Series I: Manuscripts 1960-1961, n.d.
  - Haiku beginning "Apricot leaf on gravel..." n.d., AMs, 1 p.
  - Haiku beginning "Emperor publish Entomological paper..." 1960 August 20, AMsS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Haiku beginning "great tea-master Sikyu..." 1961 June 30, AMsS, 1 p.
  - Haiku beginning "Lady No-kama-yo has arranged peaches..." n.d., AMs, 1 p.
  - Haiku beginning "Madelena, shy..." 1961 June 30, AMsS, 1 p.
  - Haiku beginning "Yamo-juri the sword-smith..." n.d., AMs, 1 p.
- Series II: Letters 1956-1883
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence H. Scott, [re his busy schedule and asks him to contact him the following week] 1956 May 27, AL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, Massachusetts, [includes brief quotes, writes that he does not like "working in the gothic mode"] 1958 March 7, APC
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [includes brief quotes] 1958 March 17, TPC
  - Guy Davenport, Boston, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [acknowledges receipt of [Leo Nikolayevich] Tolstoy note and "chinese little animals," wonders about the identity of two stamps in his possession] 1958 March 22, APCS
  - "Elder Grey" ([Guy Davenport]) to "Dear Second Cousin Hippolyte" [Laurence Scott], [acknowledges receipt of his letter as well as an invitation to dinner with T[homas] S[tearns] Eliot, asks him to visit one evening] 1958 April 26, ALS, 1 p.
  - "Silas Hugebone, Solicit." [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [sends a satirical letter offering assistance and requests information on the latter's "correspondent in Hungary, Count Dlugascz Dracula"] 1958 May 7, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes about [Marcus Tullius] Cicero] 1958 May 12, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, Michigan, [mentions a trip to New York and visits to art galleries] 1958 July 8, TL, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, South Carolina, to "Most choicy Florilector" [Laurence Scott], [comments on the latter's Greek Handschrift as very late Byzantine, writes that he has just finished a painting] 1958 August 14, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Bey Larunz" [Laurence Scott], [mentions his wife leaving and suing for divorce] 1958 August 21, ALS, 1 p.
  - "Guido da Whatever" [Guy Davenport] to "Dear Lawnse" [Laurence Scott], [makes tentative plans for their art show] 1958 August 22, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [writes brief note chiefly in Greek] 1958 November 5, APC
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott 1958 Nov, AL
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, on Christmas card, [asks to send his Christmas gift later] 1958 December 18, ANS
  - "Endymion Davenport" [Guy Davenport] to "Caro Lorenzaccio" [Laurence Scott] 1958 December 23, TL, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - "Endymion" [Guy Davenport] to "dyeuh Laonse" [Laurence Scott], [describes a visit from Peter Kramer and [Stella] and her mother and step-father] 1958 December 29, TL, 2 p. on 1.
  - "Guido" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to "Lauro caro" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions the discovery ot a [William] Blake painting in the attic at Hampden Court] 1959 January 20, TL, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport to "Lauro estimado y querido" [Laurence Scott], [mentions an interest in a young Swedish male] 1959 March 28, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport to Laurence Scott, [discusses a photograph of the young Swedish male as well as his own sexual beliefs] 1959 April 4, ALS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to "Dear maiden aunt of Ezra Pound" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [writes it was a "privilege to see Marianne Moore's letters" and to "'Tell old Ezra Pound to go start his own magazine and leave Gadfly alone'" 1959 June 2, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - "Guido" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to "Dear Lonze" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [discusses some occurrences during his trip to New York City, including a luncheon at Cosmopolitan Club with Dorothy Norman, tries to raise money for Ezra Pound] 1959 June 16, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to "Caro Lauro" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [identifies Dorothy Norman, writes more on Ezra Pound's financial dilemma, discusses Harry Goldgar's personal and emotional problems (paranoia), receives a list of people from Ezra Pound to send a copy of Gadfly1959 June 22, ALS, 2 p., on 1 l., w/env.
  - "Endymion Porter" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [acknowledges receipt of books for his birthday, apologizes for being slightly unsociable on a previous occasion, with enclosure] 1959 June 23, TL, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Boston, to "Dear Anatole France" [Laurence Scott] 1960 January 30, APCS
  - "Firestone" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to Dear Benito Mussolini & His Circle" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor 1960 February 2, TL, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - "Govey" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to "Caro Lauro" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [dicusses French author Victor Berard] 1960 February 5, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - "Andy Jackson" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to "Lonse" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [mentions the material deposited form time to time by Scott, discusses a diary of James K. Polk which he bought] 1960 April 4, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions [ ] Ruskin, Lee Lescaze, and Karl Hill] 1960 June 6, AL, 1 p., w/env.
  - "Benny" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to "Dear Monster" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [mentions "Uncle Ez" [Ezra Pound], his apartment being painted and his "new Victorian treatise on architecture"] 1960 June 9, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Cambridge, to "Dear Monster" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [expresses gratitude for images, mentions Lee Lescaze, Clarence [ ], Karl Hill, discusses the progress of his E[zra] P[ound] thesis and his "elliptical style"] 1960 June 17, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - "Ono Suzuki" [Guy Davenport], Cambridge, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses studying T.D. Suzuki and his teaching of Zen, reading Thomas Holcroft and the Drs. Kronhausen, with enclosure of "Real Haiku" and "Ersatz haiku"] 1960 June 20, AL, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [quotes and translates Theognis, along with a page of modern Japanese work] 1960 July 22, AL, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [alludes to his sexual preferences] 1960 July 27, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - "Jean" [Guy Davenport], Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [describes a day of bicycling and swimming with his young friend, Max] 1960 July 29, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Dear Lawnse" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [concerns an archeological exploration with his parents, discusses time spent with some neighborhood boys] 1960 August 1, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Lauro" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [concerns his friendship with "Tom," a former student and his failure to communicate, his "penchant for juvenile delinquents," and life in the South] 1960 August 2, ALS, 2 p., on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Caro Lauro" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [ concerns a biking expedition, the desegregation of Anderson, and letters from friends] 1960 August 4, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Dear City Mouse" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [writes personal news about receiving a letter and his "daily bike-ride and swim"] 1960 August 7, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [reveals personal thoughts, discusses a "mutely homosexual" incident in the Army] 1960 August 8, ALS, 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Lauro caro" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions "Tom" and his feelings for him, comments on Scott's visit to New Hampshire] 1960 August 10, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Lorenzaccio" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [writes that Sara [Dakin] should re-found Gadfly, mentions Marianna Moore and Ezra Pound as well as people in Anderson, expounds on sexuality] 1960 August 16, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses differences in Max and a rich boy and how it will affect their futures, mentions a letter from Tom Gleason, mentions Marianne Moore and Louis Agassiz] 1960 August 19, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Dear Lord Houghton" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [planning to go to Oconee State Park for a picnic for underprivileged children] 1960 August 23, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Laurentius Clarus" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [discusses his role in the Oconee State Park outing for poor children, his American Literature required reading list, and the Olympics] 1960 August 26, ALS, 2 p on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Dear Ignatz" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge 1960 August 27, TPC
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Dear Rudolph" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [re Marianne Moore's visit to Cambridge] 1960 August 27, TPC
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "O Wazir" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [writes a discussion of Jean-Paul Sartre's Genet and the censorship of Henry Miller, "the privilege of being understood," and mentions a letter from Austin Warren] 1960 August 28, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions reading about Emmeline Pankhurst, Marie Lloyd, and Gertrude Bell and having two new drawings for A[ustin]; W[arren]] 1960 September 2, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Most Excellent Theophilus" [Laurence Scott], Ann Arbor, [discusses his feelings after receiving a letter from Tom Gleason, Lord Byron's "extraordinary letters" and the burning of his "Henry-Miller-like autobiography"] 1960 September 2, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [discusses his findings concerning Louis Agassiz while researching for his essay] 1960 September 6, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, Pennsylvania, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [writes about activities in Anderson and mentions Louis Agassiz] 1960 September 9, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Dear Rumpus" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [acknowledges receipt of "fish-notes and the four fetching Chinese postcards," discusses his teaching agenda, mentions Catherine Drinker Bowen being a neighbor, and comments on his research on Louis Agassiz] 1960 September 21, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Cher Laurent" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [concerns some activities at Haverford, such as visiting the DuPont Gardens and giving the Arts Council Lecture for a joint Bryn Mawr-Haverford audience, discusses Lafcadio Hearn's life as written by his wife, Setsu Koizumi, mentions other reading material] 1960 October 13, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Dear Laurentino" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [writes some about Jean Genet after finishing the book, discusses in some detail Charles Norman's biography of Ezra Pound 1960 October 19, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Querido Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [re hearing a poetry reading by Jonathan Williams of the Jargen Press, mentions Lee Lescaze, Karl Hill, Louis Agassiz, Jacques Maries, Ezra Pound, Ray Steinging, and finishing his thesis on Pound] 1960 October 26, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes that Haverford wants him to stay, mentions works in progress] 1960 November 29, AL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re his empathy with troublesome young men, reflects on his time at Haverford so far] 1960 December 18, ALS, 1p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [describes some students and their academic work as well as his courses at Haverford] 1960 December 24, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [concerns life at Haverford University and applying for permanent membership of the faculty] 1961 March 14, TL, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions his thesis being approved, having dinner with Douglas Cooper, and conversing with Alice Biddle] 1961 April 23, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Hugh Kenner becoming their Shipley lecturer, receipt of a letter from Tom Gleason, Ezra Pound and some damaging papers held by Noel Stock, and a lecture on Marianne Moore] 1961 May 2, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [concerns a few students at Haverford, with color drawing of partially nude male on first page] 1961 May 6, ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re finishing the academic year at Haverford and hoping to receive his Harvard degree, mentions summer plans including a stay at a nudist camp] 1961 June 1, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re lecturing at Bryn Mawr, his thesis being judged, and Ezra Pound] 1961 June 6, TPCS
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [re a weekend trip to New York and receiving acceptance at the "suntan farm"] 1961 June 12, TPCS
  - Guy Davenport, The High Meadows, Palmerton, Pennsylvania, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [discusses his stay at the nudist camp] 1961 June 22, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [concerns a radio interview with Zelda Suplee about their visit to the nudist camp, describes his and Gordon Adams' stay at the camp] 1961 June 24, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [discusses Anderson] 1961 July 4, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [concerns research on names] 1961 July 7, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [writes brief news of former students, Tom Gleason, Gordon Adams, Nada Alexandrovna, and Lee Lascaze] 1961 July 8, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions the [Zelda Suplee] Foundation [for the promotion of Nudity], Tom Gleason, Ernest Hemingway's suicide, Haverford's resident composer John Davison, and anthropologist Rodney Needham] 1961 July 9, ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [requests him to translate a few Polish phrases found in H.S. Ede's Gaudier-Brzeska, and wants to collaborate on a book of translation and Gaudier drawings] 1961 July 14, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions Lee Lascaze, Tom Gleason, and the American space flight with Virgil I. Grissom] 1961 July 21, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [re seeing Gordon Adams, John Davison, and Charles Luddington, and mentions Ezra Pound's heart attack] 1961 September 4, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions writings of various authors, including E. C. Mullins, Ford Madox Ford, Frank Lloyd Wright, Conan Doyle, and Ezra Pound; refers to Harry Goldgar and John Edwards; his own works in progress, particularly Gadfly and Louis Agassiz; and personal news] 1961 September 30, A & TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - "Mycroft" [Guy Davenport], Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [concerns Hugh Kenner's project The Age of Pound and a visit to the campus by Irishman Sean O'Faolain, and mentions Tom Gleason, Christina R[ossetti], and his lectures on James Joyce] 1961 October 28, APCS
  - "Domvile" [Guy Davenport], Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge 1961 November 20, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [sends holiday greetings] 1961 December 19, ANS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [concerns his holiday reading, and mentions literary persons such as Ezra Pound, Ford Madox Ford, Ivor Stravinsky, and Dame Edith Sitwell] 1961 December 24, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes brief news of Gordon Adams and Tom Gleason, mentions his Wyndham Lewis lectures, and requests picutres of Scott and Marianne Moore] 1961 December 29, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses a new student, Steve, taken under his wing, and mentions Hugh Kenner's Beckett] 1962 January 10, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions seeing [Thomas Stearns] Eliot and Ezra Pound, plans with Hugh Kenner to obtain Eliot's manuscript of The Waste Land with "blue-pencilling of the Master," and students Gordon Adams, Bill Driscoll, and Steve [ ] 1962 January 14, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions [Thomas Stearns] Eliot, Gordon Adams, and his own work on "Poundiana" 1962 January 19, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes about his teaching work at Haverford and his hopes to do a course at Bryn Mawr] 1962 January 22, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes mostly about some male Haverford students in a general sexual manner, mentions upcoming visits from Gordon Adams and Tom Gleason, and thanks him for the "Poundiana"] 1962 February 5, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re a visit with Tom Gleason, John Davison, and Chass Stewart] 1962 February 9, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Lorenz" [Laurence Scott], [mentions Hugh Kenner and Gordon Adams, describes at length an adventure with two young men, Robbie [ ] and Peter Hayes] 1962 July 23, TLS, 3 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to "Dear Lawnts" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions Robbie and psychiatrist and anthropologist Ray Birdwhistell] 1962 August 6, APCS
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [discusses the inter-relationships of several people and himself] 1962 August 7, ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [writes bits of news about Gordon Adams, Lee Lascaze, Martha Emily [ ], Robbie, Peter Hayes, and Clarence [ ]] 1962 August 23, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Ann Arbor, [mentions some future plans for a trip to Europe] 1962 August 30, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions social situations with friends and attending a course on Japanese thought] 1962 October 9, TLS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions an interview of Hugh Kenner by Herbert Kenny, a weekend trip to Bennington, Vermont with John Davison, and personal news concerning friends, Robbie and Mary Ann [ ] 1962 October 15, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [asks about "the philopaidetic ... iconography situation," and mentions [John F.] Kennedy and Armageddon] 1962 October 28, TL, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [re trying to catch up on everything during Thanksgiving holiday, mentions that Ezra Pound was reported to be seen in Venice] 1962 November 25, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes about his and Robbie's plans to travel around Europe and not having his contract renewed] 1962 December 10, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Caro Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Cambride, [mentions Priscilla Buckley, Frank Meyer, Marianne Moore, writes that his trip to Europe has been cancelled, and "Stoic Comedians"] 1963 January 9, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Caro Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [re lecturing on Wyndham Lewis and Samuel Beckett, friends Mary Ann and [Robbie] 1963 January 14, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Caro Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [thanks him for several things, writes that his travelling companion to Europe will be Hugh Kenner instead] 1963 January 18, TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to "Meus amicus" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [mentions Marianne Moore, Leonard Littlefield, and Priscilla Buckley, and lists works in progress and other occurrences] 1963 April 3, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l.
  - "Mauberley" [Guy Davenport], Haverford, to "Caro Lorenzo" [Laurence Scott], Cambridge, [re trying to finish his thesis on Ezra Pound, working on Intelligence of Louis Agassiz, publishing the Stoic Comedians, taking a position at the University of Kentucky, planning a vacation with Mary Ann after plans for Europe failed, and Hugh Kenner, with ink drawing of partially nude male on first page] 1963 April 18, TLS, 3 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Marianne Moore, Robbie's departure, work on the Ezra Pound book, and finishing a poem and Archilochos] 1963 June 6, TLS, 1 p., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Anderson, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [writes news of family and himself, and a visit from Gordon Adams] 1963 July 8, ALS, 1 p.
  - Guy Davenport, Haverford, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions trip with Mary Ann and asks if Marianne Moore might want a copy of Intelligence of Louis Agassiz] 1963 August 16, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [discusses his book Intelligence of Louis Agassiz and the notion of sending a copy to Marianne Moore] 1963 September 4, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [praises his transcription of "the Hildabuch," and mentions the work of Stan Brakhage and the fact that the Indiana Press has accepted his thesis] 1963 September 15, TLS, 3 p. on 2 l.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Hugh Kenner, Archilochos, Marianne Moore, and translating Theognis] 1963 October 20, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Ezra and Dorothy Pound, Marianne Moore, the assassination of John F. Kennedy, and Mary Ann] 1963 November 30, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.
  - Guy Davenport, Lexington, to Laurence Scott, Cambridge, [mentions Hugh Kenner's lecture on Marianne Moore, his Archilochos being published next month, and Howard Nemerov's visit] 1964 January 19, TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env.